<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ToDoTui</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/projects/todotui_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/projects/todotui_project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introducing-todotui&#34;&gt;Introducing ToDoTui&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheCarton/todo_tui&#34;&gt;ToDoTui&lt;/a&gt; is a work-in-progress to-do app that runs in the terminal and isn’t just a list. Users can add tasks blazingly fast, and without removing
their hands from the keyboard. Tasks can be organized into projects, and tasks are displayed based on a simple round-robin algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/todotui_demo.gif&#34;  alt=&#34;Hello Friend&#34;  class=&#34;center&#34;  style=&#34;border-radius: 2px;&#34;    /&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;philosophy-of-use&#34;&gt;Philosophy of Use&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ToDoTui is meant to take tasks off your mind when they’re distracting you as quickly as possible, and not make matters worse by distracting you further.
Later, when you’re remembering that there was something you wanted to work on, you can quickly shuffle through your tasks and find it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introducing-todotui&#34;&gt;Introducing ToDoTui&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheCarton/todo_tui&#34;&gt;ToDoTui&lt;/a&gt; is a work-in-progress to-do app that runs in the terminal and isn’t just a list. Users can add tasks blazingly fast, and without removing
their hands from the keyboard. Tasks can be organized into projects, and tasks are displayed based on a simple round-robin algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/todotui_demo.gif&#34;  alt=&#34;Hello Friend&#34;  class=&#34;center&#34;  style=&#34;border-radius: 2px;&#34;    /&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;philosophy-of-use&#34;&gt;Philosophy of Use&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ToDoTui is meant to take tasks off your mind when they’re distracting you as quickly as possible, and not make matters worse by distracting you further.
Later, when you’re remembering that there was something you wanted to work on, you can quickly shuffle through your tasks and find it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ToDoTui wants you to make a decision about a task. It tracks how many times you skip a task, and allows you to find these often-skipped tasks and abandon them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s nothing wrong with abandoning tasks. ToDoTui is meant to help you focus on what you think is important, not pretend you’ll be able to do
every single thing that comes to your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ToDoTui wants to help you celebrate progress by tracking tasks you’ve completed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;workflow-adding-a-task&#34;&gt;Workflow: Adding a Task&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user opens ToDoTui with a new task they want ToDoTui to store. They type a simple description of a task,
and optionally give it a due date and assign it to a project. This is meant to have very few distractions,
and so does not show a list of unfinished tasks to the user while they’re trying to quickly jot down a task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;workflow-finding-a-task&#34;&gt;Workflow: Finding a Task&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user opens ToDoTui, either with a project they intend to work on or not. If they have a project in mind,
they select that project, and cycle through tasks until they see one they decide to work on. If they have no task in mind,
the default project of ToDoTui cycles through all other projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;workflow-cleaning-up-tasks&#34;&gt;Workflow: Cleaning up Tasks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default on startup, ToDoTui shows the last displayed task. A displayed task can be marked as finished, abandoned, assigned to a project,
or simply shuffled behind the other tasks. A user can also open the Very Old Tasks wizard, which displays tasks that have been skipped
many times and are long past their due dates. This encourages users to abandon tasks that, realistically, they are never going to do.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;who-is-this-luke-guy-be-brief&#34;&gt;Who is this Luke guy? Be brief.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luke is a programmer, data scientist, writer, and accidental jack-of-all trades living in Somerville, MA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;be-less-brief-and-use-the-first-person&#34;&gt;Be less brief and use the first person.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I received an M.S of Computer Science from Northeastern in 2023, and a B.S in economics in 2015. Some topics that sap a disproportionate amount of
my attention are the climate crisis, science and science communication, and political policy nerdom.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;who-is-this-luke-guy-be-brief&#34;&gt;Who is this Luke guy? Be brief.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luke is a programmer, data scientist, writer, and accidental jack-of-all trades living in Somerville, MA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;be-less-brief-and-use-the-first-person&#34;&gt;Be less brief and use the first person.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I received an M.S of Computer Science from Northeastern in 2023, and a B.S in economics in 2015. Some topics that sap a disproportionate amount of
my attention are the climate crisis, science and science communication, and political policy nerdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also worked a lot of jobs. Most recently I was a line cook; but I&amp;rsquo;ve also been a lifeguard, a dispatcher at Amazon logistics, a customer
service representative and part-time data entry automation clerk, and a teacher&amp;rsquo;s assistant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is my ambition to use computers and technology to solve the big problems and further human knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Tutorials</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 12:25:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tutorials-are-awful&#34;&gt;Tutorials are awful&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a graph of tutorials-per-capita consumption over time. For most of human history, we&amp;rsquo;re blissfully free of them.
No blog posts about git rebase, no semi-official Reddit pages about where the Windows control panel is hiding, no
desperate smartphone-rendered YouTube videos on how to light a pilot light two hours before service starts. Alright
that last one might be a little specific. Regardless, suddenly in the 20th century, it&amp;rsquo;s hundreds or maybe thousands of tutorials per year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tutorials-are-awful&#34;&gt;Tutorials are awful&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a graph of tutorials-per-capita consumption over time. For most of human history, we&amp;rsquo;re blissfully free of them.
No blog posts about git rebase, no semi-official Reddit pages about where the Windows control panel is hiding, no
desperate smartphone-rendered YouTube videos on how to light a pilot light two hours before service starts. Alright
that last one might be a little specific. Regardless, suddenly in the 20th century, it&amp;rsquo;s hundreds or maybe thousands of tutorials per year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they never work!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, that&amp;rsquo;s not true of course. I think the frustration I feel from them though is instructive. Because, while of course
there are actually bad tutorials, mostly I think tutorials are pretty carefully constructed. But they&amp;rsquo;re frozen in time.
And the most needed tutorials are technical tutorials, and are you even programming if you&amp;rsquo;re not using the absolute
most-bleeding edge Javascript framework?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have to sweat the details with technical work. The compiler cares if you forget a semicolon, and those technical details
change all too quickly for technical tutorials to have much staying power. While ancient historians are allowed lengthy digressions
on the nature of humanity and power that may ring true a thousand years later, a technical tutorial won&amp;rsquo;t even know what text
editor you&amp;rsquo;ll be using in two decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But also, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be great if the tutorials were a compiled language? Obsolete references getting automatically flagged for review?
Code examples runnable within the text itself?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, that&amp;rsquo;s thinking too small. The tutorial &lt;em&gt;itself&lt;/em&gt; should solve the problem! A computer can be made to always interpret the text
the same way, so these tutorials could be exchanged between writers to solve all sorts of problems!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oops, I re-invented programming languages again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This kind of thinking, however, is what leads to my interest in Nix. The kinds of problems we solve tend to need to be solved over and
over, and it is my hope the Nix&amp;rsquo;s emphasis on reproducibility will make these not-very-new new problems easier to address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this Hugo website is running on a NixOs computer in my room. Nix handles the installation and configuration of the software. So,
I write Nix files that tell the computer where to get the blog, the Hugo theme, the NGINX reverse proxy, the Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt certificate,
and maybe some other stuff that I forgot about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was this the easiest way to get a website up and running? Absolutely not. But it was the most interesting. So big shout out to
Janne Pulkkinen, aka Matoking, whose tutorial &lt;a href=&#34;https://matoking.com/blog/2023/07/08/deploying-hugo-site-using-nixos-and-nginx/&#34;&gt;Deploying Hugo site using NixOS and nginx&lt;/a&gt;
was extremely helpful! And my advice to myself when I&amp;rsquo;m feeling frustrated with a technical problem and a tutorial is: It&amp;rsquo;s
probably not the tutorials fault.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
